cakephp.org 2019-09-24

# CakePHP - Build fast, grow solid | Privacy policy

The privacy of our visitors to cakephp.org is important to us.

At cakephp.org, we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit cakephp.org, and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties. 

We collect information that you provide to us directly when you use our services. What we collect: 

### Log Files:

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site. 

### Cookies:

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site.

What are cookies

Cookies are small pieces of text sent by your web browser by a website you visit. A cookie file is stored in your web browser and allows the Service or a third-party to recognize you and make your next visit easier and the Service more useful to you. 

Cookies can be "persistent" or "session" cookies.

How CakePHP uses cookies

When you use and access the Service, we may place a number of cookies files in your web browser.

We use cookies for the following purposes: to enable certain functions of the Service, to provide analytics, to store your preferences, to enable advertisements delivery, including behavioral advertising. 

We use both session and persistent cookies on the Service and we use different types of cookies to run the Service: 

Essential cookies. We may use essential cookies to authenticate users and prevent fraudulent use of user accounts. 

### My.cakephp.org account information (only specific to my.cakephp.org user sign up)

Account information: To create an account, you must provide a username and password. Your username is public, and it doesn’t have to be related to your real name. You may also provide an email address. We also store your user account preferences and settings. 

_Content you submit._ We collect the content you submit to the Services. This includes your posts and comments including saved drafts, your messages with other users (e.g., private messages, chats, and modmail). Your content may include text, links, images, gifs, and videos. 

_Actions you take._ We collect information about the actions you take when using the Services. This includes your interactions with content, like voting, saving, hiding, and reporting. It also includes your interactions with other users, such as following, friending, and blocking. We collect your interactions with communities, like your subscriptions or moderator status. 

_Transactional information._ If you purchase products or services from us (e.g., CakeFest, CakePHP training), we will collect certain information from you, including your name, address, email address, and information about the product or service you are purchasing. Payments are processed by third-party payment processors (e.g., PayPal), so please refer to the applicable processor’s terms and privacy policy for more information about how payment information is processed and stored. 

_Other information._ You may choose to provide other information directly to us. For example, filling out your personal information on your user profile. 

### How We Use Information About You

We use information about you to:

* Provide, maintain, and improve the Services;
* Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, invoices and other support and administrative messages;
* Provide customer service;
* Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, and events, and provide other news and information we think will be of interest to you (for information about how to opt out of these communications, see “Your Choices” below);
* Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with our Services;

### Advertising:

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). 

### Analytics Partners

We use [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/) to help analyze usage and traffic for our Services. As an example, we may use analytics partners to analyze and measure, in the aggregate, the number of unique visitors to our Services. 

### Deleting Your Account

You may delete your account information at any time from the user preferences page. When you delete your account, your profile is no longer visible to other users and disassociated from content you posted under that account. 

### Information Security

We take measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. For example, we use HTTPS while information is being transmitted We also enforce technical and administrative access controls to limit which of our employees have access to non-public personal information. 

### Data Retention

We store the information we collect for as long as it is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it. We may retain certain information for legitimate business purposes or as required by law. 

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at community@cakephp.org
